

# Peter Harvey

coderfoundry.com/peterharvey

# FRAMEWORKS & PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES

C#
MVC
.NET
JavaScript
HTML5
CSS
ASP.NET
SQL
Bootstrap
JQuery
LINQ
AngularJS
WebAPI

# CODER FOUNDRY

1231 Shields Road, Suite 5 Kernersville, NC 27284

(336) 231-8632

partnerships@coderfoundry.com

This resume contains information furnished by the candidate and has not been independently verified by Coder Foundry, LLC.

This information is privileged, confidential, and to be used solely by the individual and entity to which it has been submitted.

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

### **Coder Foundry, Web Software Engineer**

Kernersville, NC · July 2016-September 2016

- Created a personal portfolio and blog website using C#, MVC5 and JavaScript.
- Created a fully functional MVC bug tracker web application, from scratch, implementing enhanced security and file uploading features.
- Created a fully functioning car finder web application. Accessed NHTSA's car recalls database using WebAPI. Included images using Bing's WebAPI.
- Created a fully functional financial portal web application using .NET MVC framework. Composed dynamic front-end design using partial views and AJAX.

### Park Sterling Bank, Loan Portfolio Analyst

Rock Hill, SC · January 2014-July 2016

- Developed monthly risk management reporting material used by the Director of Builder Finance to measure performance with respect to soundness, profitability and growth.
- Managed the pipeline of new credit requests and renewal activity of the portfolio for completion.
- Monitored individual borrower performance on a monthly basis based on financial metrics, global inventory composition and performance under the bank's guidance line
- Prepared weekly loan committee presentations to jointly present credits and field questions with Loan Officer.

#### Wells Fargo Bank, Loan Underwriter III

Charlotte, NC · February 2013-January 2014

- Acted as point of contact for non-decision making partners to gather information, make appropriate lending decisions and explain rationale behind credit decision.
- Responsible for reviewing, analyzing, approving and underwriting large, unusual or complex individual consumer requests and products within company and industry quidelines.
- Prepared formal credit analysis reports and compliance reviews.
- Assisted with re-negotiations of loans based on lending guidelines.

#### Bluetarp Financial Inc., Senior Commercial Credit Analyst II

Charlotte, NC & Portland, ME · November 2009–February 2013

- Underwrote new credit applications and existing customer accounts to determine credit worthiness, appropriate credit line, and payment terms based on internal credit underwriting policies and government standards.
- Gathered and assessed relevant information about customer's business and credit history, including consumer and commercial credit reports, bank and vendor references, financial statements, tax returns, statements of cash-flow and balance sheets.
- Completed thorough write-up analysis of larger more complex credit extensions.
- Recommend high risk credit and collection situations to loss mitigation team for escalated action.
- Coached and mentored lower-level analysts on decision-making and departmental processes and policies, and provided performance feedback to their supervisors.

#### Bank of America (Legacy MBNA), Senior Credit Analyst II

Belfast, ME · 2001–2009

- Underwrote consumer loans based on escalated requests and strategy generated risk detection reviews.
- Evaluated credit bureaus, account history, and customer provided information to reach determination regarding customer relationship with the bank.
- Pro-actively contacted customers regarding financial stability commitments and to assess potential account risks.
- Provided credit solutions and counseling to customers experiencing financial hardship.
- Underwrote credit card applications, credit reports, tax documents and bank references to determine or adjust customer credit lines; determined applicant's credit worthiness based on ability and willingness to repay; generated revenue through transfer transactions and additional bank product sales.

## **EDUCATION**

University of New Hampshire, Bachelors of Science in Forestry

Durham, NH . 1998



1231 Shields Road, Suite 5 Kernersville, NC 27284

(336) 231-8632

partnerships@coderfoundry.com

This resume contains information furnished by the candidate and has not been independently verified by Coder Foundry, LLC.

This information is privileged, confidential, and to be used solely by the individual and entity to which it has been submitted.